

tOlia.gm@gmail.com t.me/AnatolyPozdniakov



Senior Java Developer

PERSONAL PROFILE

Java developer with a background in Big Data. have experience building distributed systems, data processing pipelines, web applications development, and various types of integrations. Passionate about development experience improvements, process automation, and DevOps practices. I am interested in distributed systems, high-load applications, and clean architectures. I am always ready to learn something new and improve my skills.

TECH STACK

Languages: Java, Scala, Python, JavaScript

Frameworks: Spring (Boot, Rest, Integration, WS), Spark Databases: PostgreSQL, ScyllaDB, ElasticSearch, Vertica

Messaging: Kafka, RabbitMQ

Infra: Linux, Docker, Ansible, Gitlab CI

EXPERIENCE

6/2022 - present

Senior Java Developer

T1-consulting [t1-consulting.ru]

- Designing architecture for search application inside a platform
- Developing MVPs for search services: Kafka interactions, full-text search, API
- Collaborating with teams inside a platform to create integrations. Designing and implementing integrations

Java / ElasticSearch / ScyllaDb / Kafka

6/2020 - 6/2022

Senior Big Data Engineer

JettyCloud [jettycloud.com] / RingCentral [ringcentral.com]

- Implemented new pipelines for data processing. Delivered application data from AppsFlyer platform, implemented data ingestion from SalesForce
- Adopted and modernized previous solutions to meet new compliance. Migrated existing pipelines from Hadoop to Spark standalone architecture
- Took part in the disaster recovery project. Implemented Kafka interactions between services of main and recovery clusters
- Worked on integration tests infrastructure. Kickstarted a new approach to integration testing. Tuned CI/CD pipeline to automate tests. Implemented integration tests approach for 2 projects

/ Scala / Hadoop / Spark / Amazon S3 / Vertica / Snowflake / Kafka

2/2018 - 6/2020 2 years 5 months

Senior Java Developer

Luxoft [luxoft.com]

- Developed mail sorting automation application for RussianPost. Added functionality to work with international mail
- Created new services to interact with industrial sorting machines. Upgrade allowed to add sorting machine in unified mail infrastructure
- Developed new analytics service which allowed analysis mail status and generate reports
- Implemented integrations inside the RussianPost platform with different protocols: Kafka, SOAP,

Spring(Boot/WS/Integration/AMQP) / PostgreSQL / JavaScript / React / RabbitMQ

4/2016 - 2/2018 1year 11 months

Java developer

GazInformService [gaz-is.ru]

- Worked as part of a cross-functional team to develop core of Identity Management System
- Collaborated with integration team to provide a wide range of integrations
- Planned and implemented new features for the system

Java / OSGI / Docker / PostgreSQL / ElasticSearch / Activiti BPMN

EDUCATION

2004 - 2010

Specialist Degree

Baltic State Technical University "Voenmeh" D.F. Ustinov

Automated information processing and management systems

LANGUAGES

Russian - Native English - Advanced French - Beginner

CERTIFICATES

- Luxoft-training: Spring Framework 5 for Application Development
- Luxoft-training: OWASP Top 10 Security Risks
- Rebrain workshops: Logs (ELK stack), PostgreSQL, Python